## **GUDDY M SABU**

D6 306, Purva Windermere, Pallikarani, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 600100 Mob: +91-9791074285

guddysabu@gmail.com

#### - SUMMARY -

To pursue a challenging professional career in an IT service firm that would provide a platform to utilize my skills and explore my potentials as a software engineer for the overall progress of my Organization and my own personal value addition / advancement. With over 5 + years of experience, my forte includes proficiency in IT skills and personnel management.

#### CORE COMPETENCIES & SKILLS

- Selenium , Java, JEST, API Testing
- Manual Testing
- Eclipse, Postman, Visual Studio Code
- Page Object Model, TestNG Spring MVC, Cucumber framework
- MYSQL, RDB and DynamoDB

- JIRA,CDETS, TIMS
- Staff training and development
- Operational leadership
- Good communication skill
- Requirements gathering

EXPERIENCE -

### HCL LIMITED Chennai, TN

Lead Engineer June 2021 till date

#### Project Name: CX Partner Portal / Client - Cisco Systems

- Involved in completed end to end testing using cucumber Java and JEST framework and was responsible for preparing test plans, test cases including functional, UAT and sanity along with regression testing during each release
- Interacted with the Engineering team during requirement gathering, analysis and followed Agile methodology
- Used AWS services including RDB, DynamoDB and AWS lambdas
- Performed Manual and automation testing (For UI and API)
- Involved in maintaining bug reports, analysing the report and maintain the defect lifecycle and getting the defect closed. Used CDETS and JIRA to mark defects and to track the features and also conducted knowledge sharing sessions across QA teams.
- Attended daily stand up and retrospective meetings
- The technology / platforms used in the project: Cucumber, Java, java script, Postman, JEST, cypress, Amazon Web Services, TIMS, CDETS, Confluence, JIRA, Kubernetes

#### **ALTIMETRIK INDIA**

Chennai, TN

Quality Engineer Sep 2016 to Jun 2018

#### Project Name: Atifin /Client -Altimetrik India

- Involved in completed end to end testing using Java Selenium framework
  and was responsible for preparing test plans, test cases and carried out functional testing, regression testing
  and Sanity testing
- Involved in API testing using Postman

- Interacted with the Client during requirement gathering, analysis and followed Agile methodology
- Experienced in Bug tracking and reporting using defect management Tools like JIRA and Test link
- Involved in Mobile automation using Appium
- Attended daily stand up and retrospective meetings
- The technology /platforms used in the project: Java, Selenium, Javascript, Html, SQL queries, Postman, Appium, JIRA, Confluence, Test link

#### **TECH MAHINDRA**

Chennai, TN

Software Engineer Jan 2012 to Sep 2014

Tech Mahindra Limited is an Indian multinational provider of Information Technology (IT), networking technology solutions, Integrated Engineering Solutions (IES) and Business Process Outsourcing (BPO) to various industry verticals and horizontals.

- Project Name : Rupee / Client: State Bank of India
- The project was part of the client's online banking remittance at handling remittance transactions from other countries to India
- It served to all countries for transaction of funds between any two accounts through the exchange company's SBI accounts
- Actively participated in all QA and testing activities during UAT and PROD SDLC
- · Actively participated in smoke, functional and ad-hoc testing
- Tested Applications compatibility on different browser versions (IE, Firefox)
- Prepared Test Reports and submitted the bug findings to the JIRA defect tracking system
- Involved in defect reporting, defect tracking and defect reproducing
- The technology / platforms used in the project: Java Spring, Unix batch jobs, jsp, java script, IBM WebSphere service, manual testing, Oracle DB

# EDUCATION —

 M. TECH: COMPUTER SCIENCE SRM University, Chennai, TN, India

2011

• **B.E**: COMPUTER SCIENCE **Karunya University**, Coimbatore, TN, India

2007

2016

PRIMARY & SECONDARY EDUCATION
 Mahatma Gandhi Public School, Ambadimala, KL, India

#### KEY PROFESSIONAL SYNOPSIS

- Expertise in Automation Framework designing and implementation in Web
- Experienced in Mobile Testing
- Preparation of Automation test scripts using Selenium and Java
- Experienced in Functional testing, Web Services Testing, Regression Testing
- Experienced in Selenium/Web Driver Automation
- Experienced in test management tools to manage and maintain the requirements, develop test cases & procedures and test scripts
- Good knowledge of testing process, test tools, creation and understanding of testing artifacts like test plan, test case, test execution
- Good knowledge of Software Development Life Cycle(SDLC) and Software Testing Life Cycle(STLC)
- Experienced in Bug tracking and reporting using Defect Management Tools (Jira &Test link)
- Knowledge of Testing Terminologies, Verification, Validation, Levels of testing and Testing Techniques.

• Date of Birth : 22 May 1989

• Status : Married and has a daughter. My husband works for MRF Ltd, Chennai